<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<string_table>

	<string id="st_bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_descr">
		<text>A common elastic gauze bandage made of soft fabric and a small dressing pad. It is widely used for first aid to wounds, together with additional medical gauze and topical antibiotics if needed. It is wrapped tightly around the affected are to stop heavy bleeding and lower the risk of secondary infection in the field. It is a cheap entry-level option to more widely preferred military-grade field dressings.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (roller gauze)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major bleeding control\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_bandage_army">
		<text>Military Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_army_descr">
		<text>A military-issue emergency bandage made of dense, elastic fabric with a sterile dressing pad and a plastic clip on one end to secure it in place after application. It is widely used to dress wounds, stop heavy bleeding, and prevent secondary infection in the field. It is a reliable high-quality alternative to cheaper stock of first aid items.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (clip)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major bleeding control\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
		<text>Vikasolum</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
		<text>A medication containing the synthetic naphthoquinone Menadione (also called Vitamin K) that promotes blood coagulation and counter-acts heavy bleeding and hemorrhages. It is carried and used as a common emergency treatment for moderate injuries in the field and may also be used as augmentive treatment together with physical wound dressings (like bandages) to accelerate wound healing and prevent critical blood loss.
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_drug_antidot">
		<text>IP2 Antitoxin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot_descr">
		<text>An experimental substance comprising of several antidotes, including metoclopramidum, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxin and other compounds. The drug is used to inject a range of antibiotics to neutralize natural poisons, together with synthetic poison absorbers, into the bloodstream. Antitoxins are not commonly used in the Zone as most stalkers rely on more expensive situation-appropriate protective equipment like hazard protection suits with dedicated oxygen supply. However, IP2 is used for scenarios with only brief expected exposure, as augmentation to worn protective gear, and in expeditions with limites supplies or funds. Side effects include nausea, dry mouth, and skin irritability.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate toxin resistance\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_jgut_zhgut">
		<text>Tourniquet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jgut_descr">
		<text>A haemostatic rubber tourniquet for rapid treatment of arterial bleeding. It is manufactured from durable, stretch-resistant rubber for maximum efficacy. The device is applied proximal to the injury site and cinched tightly to occlude blood flow, then secured with a reliable locking mechanism. Due to the risk of tissue necrosis, it is critical to release the tourniquet within 15-20 minutes. Regular inspection for wear and elasticity is recommended to ensure optimal performance. Reusing an already applied tourniquet is not advised.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] major bleeding control\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_yadylin">
		<text>Yadylin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_yadylin_descr">
		<text>A strong nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) for managing varying levels of pain. Yadulin features quick onset analgesic effects, an increased production of adrenaline in the body, and blocks enzymes responsible for inflammation and swelling. Has frequent side effects of nausea. A common pain relief drug in the Zone, though arguably more popular for its versatility in the synthesis of other compounds.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effects\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] causes nausea\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_medkit">
		<text>First Aid Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_descr">
		<text>An AI-2 individual first aid kit (Аптечка Индивидуальная) with various civilian-grade items for treating wounds, pain, and low levels of radiation exposure. The kit was developed as a standard service first aid kit for various defence and law enforcement agencies and civil defense forces of the USSR. Some of the original components may have been swapped out for modern analogs for its distribution and use in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow usage (field kit)\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate health recovery\n 
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor bleeding control\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor limb recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor radiation treatment\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_medkit_army">
		<text>Military Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
		<text>A specialized first aid kit for use by military combatants. The kit contains blood coagulants, painkillers, antibiotics, immunostimulants, and radiation-countering substances. It also includes a single-use kit for removing bullets and other foreign fragments from the body. Primarily issued to military personnel and their associates, commonly imported via offical supply routes.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow usage (field kit)\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] major health recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate bleeding control\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor radiation treatment\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_medkit_science">
		<text>Expeditionary Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
		<text>A specialized first aid kit developed and used by research personnel in the Zone. The kit contains blood coagulants, painkillers, antibiotics, immunostimulants, and is additionally stocked with experimental substances to counter minor to moderate radiation poisoning. It also includes a single-use kit for removing bullets and other foreign fragments from the body. The item is based off parts from available military medkits but adds neuroprotectives and compounds to flush absorbed radiation.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific item\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow usage (field kit)\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] major health recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate bleeding control\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate radiation treatment\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_survival_kit">
		<text>Survival Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_survival_kit_descr">
		<text>A custom-assembled survival kit with high-quality tools and items for wound dressing, disinfection, and pain relief in the field. It contains bandages, antiseptics, painkillers, radiation-absorbing drugs, light antitoxins, and emergency rations. For severe injuries, it also contains a compact set of surgical tools, including sewing needles and leather strips for splinting limbs. It provides an all-in-one treatment option, though it is usually expensive to assemble and acquire.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_salicidic_acid">
		<text>Ibuprofen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_salicidic_acid_descr">
		<text>Common analgesic medication in the nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) class used for treating minor to moderate pain. Ibuprofen works by inhibiting the production of prostaglandins, chemicals that promote inflammation, pain, and fever in the body, it is fast-acting, well tolerated, and cheap. Commonly used to treat minor injuries and headaches.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_stim_impro">
		<text>Stimpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_impro_descr">
		<text>An injectable stimulant delivery package for use in the field. Contains a composition of agents with analgetic and analeptic effects. This type of stimpack is produced directly by factions in the Zone with an unknown blend of imported and synthesized substances and questionable purity. Frequent side effects include headaches, paraesthesia, and considerable increase in nutritional demand. Popular medical item used among novices due to its low price compared to imported medical supplies and wide availability.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] zone-produced item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate health recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_stim_military">
		<text>Military Stimpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_military_descr">
		<text>A military-grade injectable stimulant delivery package for use by combatants in the field. Contains a composition of potent agents with analgetic and analeptic effects. This type of stimpack is widely distributed to military personnel operating in the Zone and imported from outside pharmaceutical suppliers. Designed as an emergency measure in life-threatening situations. Its side effects include nausea, headaches and an increase in nutritional demand.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] major health recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_stim_scientic">
		<text>Expeditionary Stimpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_stim_scientic_descr">
		<text>An injectable stimulant delivery package for use by research personnel in the field. It contains a composition of potent agents with analgetic, analeptic, and radiation-countering effects. This type of stimpack is commonly used by researchers and their associates, specifically designed for high-risk expeditions into the Zone. Developed by one of Kiev's defence research institutes in a line-up of other gear and equipment for exclusion zone research. Its chemical blend has a lower side effects profile than other packages, slight nausea, headaches, and increased nutritional demand may occur. The item is based off parts from available military medkits but adds neuroprotectives and compounds to flush absorbed radiation.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] major health recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb recovery\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate radiation treatment\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_cocaine">
		<text>Cocaine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cocaine_descr">
		<text>A tropane alkaloid acting as a powerful central nervous system stimulant with euphoric effects and heightened energy levels and wakefulness. The duration of its effects depend on the mode of administration and substance purity. Common side effects include anxiety, paranoia, and restlessness. Used both recreationally and practically in the field to counter drowsiness. Some factions openly distribute it among their members while use in the Zone in general is not overly common.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate stimulant\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_adrenalin">
		<text>Epinephrine Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_adrenalin_descr">
		<text>A shot containing Epinephrine (also known as adrenalin), a hormone and a neurotransmitter. When released in the body, it acts rapidly in regulating heart rate, blood vessel and air passage diameters, metabolic shifts, and triggers instant energy production within cells throughout the body. Medically, epinephrine is used to treat anaphylaxis, cardiac arrest, and superficial bleeding. In the field, Epinephrine can be used as an emergency stimulant to counteract drowsiness and fatigue.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] major stimulant\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_morphine">
		<text>Morphine Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_morphine_descr">
		<text>An iron ampoule containing morphine, designed as field equipment for military field personnel. Morphine is regarded as the gold standard of opioid analgesics, used to relieve acute pain levels. Like other opioids, such as oxycodone, hydromorphone, and diacetylmorphine (heroin), morphine acts directly on the central nervous system (CNS). Serious side effects include nausea, low blood pressure, and increased nutritional demand after comedown. Morphine is stocked by medical personnel in the Zone and often carried as emergency relief for severe physical injuries.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor bleeding control\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major limb triage\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_analgin">
		<text>Metamizole Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_analgin_descr">
		<text>An iron ampoule containing a combination of metamizole and an antihemorrhagic agent, designed as field equipment for military field personnel. Metamizole is a strong non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID), effective in treating moderate to intense pain and fever. Side effects include nausea, weakness, increased nutritional demand, and delayed onset leukopenia and agranulocytosis. The substance blend is often stocked by military personnel in the Zone for use by medical staff.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] very minor bleeding control\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb triage\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate analgesic effect\n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_antibio_sulfad">
		<text>Sulfadimethoxine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antibio_sulfad_descr">
		<text>An effective sulfonamide antimicrobial medication used to treat infections and diseases caused by bacteria. Sulfadimethoxine is a bacteriostatic agent that works by blocking synthesis of folic acid, a key component in the production of DNA and RNA. While the drug's primary function is to act against bacteria, including E. coli, Salmonella, and Staphylococcus, it also has an observable effect against some anomalous toxins and effects of light radiation exposure. Side effects include headaches, digestive disorders, skin rashes, fevers, and leukopenia.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor radiation resistance\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor toxicity resistance\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_analgetic">
		<text>Diclofenac</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_analgetic_descr">
		<text>A non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) from the group of phenylacetic acid derivatives, commonly used as an analgetic in the treatment of mild to moderate pain, migraines, inflammation, and swelling. It features a considerable side effects profile, including headaches, dizziness, drowsiness, and rarely, memory disorders, disorientation, and general irritability. While being phased out as a common painkiller, it expired stock still made its way from warehouse clearances into the Zone and taken for the treatment of severe injuries when better alternatives can not be procured.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] very minor health recovery\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] very minor bleeding control\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_antibio_chlor">
		<text>Chlortetracycline</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antibio_chlor_descr">
		<text>A tetracycline antibiotic with antiprotozoal and antibacterial effects. It was the first tetracycline identified and the second antibiotic agent developed after penicillin. This class of medication works by inhibiting protein synthesis in the mRNA translation complex, among other mechanisms. It is effective against a broad spectrum of bacteria, but also against viruses, and some conditions not spread by infection. It is used in the Zone to guard against specific environmental hazards, often in combination with other substances. Side effects may include nausea, phototoxicity, digestive problems, allergic reactions, and rarely, headaches.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor radiation protection\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor toxicity resistance\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector">
		<text>Radioprotectant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector_descr">
		<text>A medication containing B190 indraline radioprotectant, commonly included in medkits issued to nuclear power plant staff and military personnel tasked to operate in heavily irradiated environments. Effectively reduces the effects of gamma radiation on live tissue and prevents absorption in the body. Must be consumed before exposure, does not aid in the removal of already absorbed radionucleides. Used in the Zone as a more potent alternative to iodide and as a preemptive measure to not require more drastic post-exposure treatment, like Amiprodine or Hipyridine injections that come with broader side effects profiles.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate radiation protection\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_antirad_cystamine">
		<text>Amiprodine Cx</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_cystamine_descr">
		<text>A combination medication for the treatment of light to moderate radiation exposure consisting of a broad-spectrum cytoprotective and radioprotective agent and Prussian Blue, a chelating agent that binds absorbed radionucleides in the body. It provides protection from radiation-induced cell damage and has antioxidant and inflammation-reducing effects. Developed for use by trauma and recovery teams in nuclear desaster and conflict zones, widely carried and used in the Zone as a more accessible and tolerable alternative to more aggressive anti-radiation infusions. Side effects include nausea, flushing, chest pain, upset stomach, constipation, and loss of consciousness.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor radiation treatment\n
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_antirad">
		<text>Hipyridine Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_descr">
		<text>A highly potent combination preparation of Ca-DTPA (calcium diethylenetriamine pentaacetate) and HOPO, an experimental octadentate hydroxypyridinone ligand, for the treatment of acute and emergency radiation exposure. Both compounds act by binding radical radionuclides in the body, preventing traumatic cell damage, and accelerate flushing radioactive material before irreversible damage can occur. The substance is combined with a light antiemetic to counter-act adverse reactions of nausea. Side effects include nausea, chills, fever, itching, muscle cramps, as well as headaches, drowsiness, and metallic taste in the mouth. Hipyridine binds to various vital minerals, replenishment after ingestion is advised.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate satiety drain\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major radiation treatment\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_rebirth">
		<text>Axyltallisal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rebirth_descr">
		<text>An extremely potent, highly experimental regenerative drug. The compound was developed by Zone researchers as part of an interdisciplinary study on triage and recovery after severe bodily trauma and serious anomalous field exposure. The drug is assumed to contain volatile neurogenetics, neuroprotectants, immunotherapeutics, analeptics, and additional unknown agents; its official composition was never published. Intended to be used in a controlled and safe environment. When ingested, the patient will enter a short-lasting comatose state while the drug induces an extreme state of physical and neurological regeneration. The patient should regain consciousness after the effect naturally wears off. Side effects of repeated uses are unknown. For its near-miraculous beneficial effects, it is informally called "Rebirth".\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] experimental item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] anesthetic (unconsciousness)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major health recovery\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major radiation treatment\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
		<text>Anabiotic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
		<text>A highly experimental research chemical developed as a last resort for surviving direct exposure to an emission, with a drastic mode of effect and an overwhelming side effects profile. It is an unknown combination of sodium thiopental, a rapid-onset barbiturate anesthetic, and other sedatives that dramatically slow metabolic processes in the body to a state of suspended animation. A second stage nonbenzodiazepine is released on an organic fuse that lasts for the approximate duration of an emission and restores bodily function and consciousness. Even one-time use of anabiotics can have permanent adverse effects on the user, the extent of which are unknown, not including nervous system damage sustained from direct emission exposure. If no certain alternatives are available, lay down on the ground in fetal position, shielding head and torso, ingest on emission build-up, and wait for onset of sedative effects. After successful reanimation, ensure proper hydration, nutrition, and medical attention. Should not be combined with other substances.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] experimental item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] anesthetic (unconsciousness)\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] major emission survival chance\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_tetanus">
		<text>Oxycodone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_tetanus_descr">
		<text>A semi-synthetic opioid for the treatment of moderate to severe and persistent pain and use as a cough suppressant. This variant combines dihydrohydroxycodeinone with acetaminophen, a non-opioid analgesic, and antipyretic (a combination sold under the brand name Vicodin, Lortab, and others). The medication induces euphoria and sedation, it is commonly abused for recreational use. It has a high chance for addiction and its side effects include nausea, drowsiness, constipation, and respiratory problems in higher doses. In the field, it may be used as a painkiller after sustaining physical injuries, especially to rest and recover.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor health recovery\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_sleepingpills">
		<text>Diazepam</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sleepingpills_descr">
		<text>A benzodiazepine derivative with sedative, hypnotic, and anxiolytic properties, increasing effects of the GABA neurotransmitter. It is used to treat anxiety, insomnia, seizures, and as a general sedative. While short-term use is considered reasonably safe, prolonged use carries risk of dependence and cognitive issues. Frequent side effects include nausea, drowsiness, amnesia, and confusion. In the Zone, it is used primarily as a sleeping aid to counter stress, anxiety, and sleeplessness.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate fatigue\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor antipsychotic\n
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_antiemetic">
		<text>Etperazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antiemetic_descr">
		<text>A moderately potent antipsychotic medication of the phenothiazine class with antiallergic, sedative, miorelaxing, and antiemetic effects, acting by blocking Dopamine D2 receptors in the mesocortical and mesolimbic systems. It is used in the treatment of psychosis, hallucinations, schizophrenia, mild to moderate psychomotor agitation, and as an antiemetic. In the Zone, it is used for resistance to the effects of mind-affecting hazards. Side effects include nausea, disorientation, and apathy. Prolonged exposure to cognition-affecting fields is highly discouraged, wearing properly shielding headgear is advised.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate antipsychotic\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
		<text>Haloperidol</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
		<text>A potent psychotropic medication, often resold as a preparation under the colloquial brand "Psy Block" for resistance to the effects of mind-affecting hazards found in the Zone. Haloperidol is a potent first generation antipsychotic used in the treatment of acute psychosis, hallucinations, hyperactive delirium, schizophrenia, severe nausea from the effects of radiation therapy, and as an antiemetic. Ingestion induces short-term alexithymia (emotional blindness) and may cause side effects of nausea, disorientation, and apathy. Prolonged exposure to cognition-affecting fields is highly discouraged, wearing properly shielding headgear is advised.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] experimental item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major antipsychotic\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_surginst">
		<text>Surgical Instruments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_surginst_descr">
		<text>Medical tools that belong to a surgical field kit for emergency procedures. Can either be combined with other items to assemble a proper kit or used as-is for emergency interventions. Without a proper surgery kit, direct use will require disinfection and bandaging.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor limb triage\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor surgical trauma\n
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_zagustin">
		<text>Tranexyban</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zagustin_descr">
		<text>An antifibrinolytic agent for treatment and prevention of major hemorrhaging and excessive menstruation. Tranexamic acid is a synthetic derivative of lysine and acts by preventing the breakdown of fibrin, allowing sustained blood clotting and control bleeding. Side effects are rare, with low chances for seizures, altered vision, and anaphylactic shock; hydration is recommended. The drug is commonly carried by medical and military personnel in the Zone.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor bleeding control\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor bleeding resistance\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_propital">
		<text>Fluorapine Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_propital_descr">
		<text>A military-issue injector containing a moderate metabolic stimulant and a mix of purine and pyrimidine analog cytotoxic substances. Its stimulant part acts to accelerate wound-healing processes in the body, while the cytotoxic substances aim to target and destroy damaged cells and pathogens. The drug was originally developed from pharmaceutical anti-cancer trials and selected for military use for its effect on trauma recovery times. It is used to triage physical injuries in the field when proper medical care can not be provided. Side effects include chest pain, fever, bleeding, and increased nutritional demand.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor health recovery\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor bleeding resistance\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_etg">
		<text>SJ-I Combat Stimulant Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_etg_descr">
		<text>A military-issue stimulant to increase physical capabilities, alertness, and cognitive performance, intended for use in combat scenarios. It contains part epinephrine, part pipradrol, a mild central nervous system stimulant and NDRI, and part metamizole, an ampyrone sulfonate group compound with analgesic and antipyretic effects. In combination, the shot provides an acute boost to physical and psychological resilience, even in high stress environments. Side effects are generally lower than other combat stimulant pens and may include insomnia, tachycardia, anxiety, and rarely hypertension, euphoria, depression, psychosis, and others. SJ-I is distributed, usually as a pen injector, to military personnel set to perform under extreme conditions for longer periods of time. Among the SJ class pens, it is well tolerated and has fewer adverse effects.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate stimulant effects\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate analgesic effects\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor antipsychotic effects\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_sj1">
		<text>SJ-V Combat Stimulant Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sj1_descr">
		<text>A military-issue stimulant to increase physical capabilities, alertness, and cognitive performance, intended for use in combat scenarios. It contains part epinephrine, part amfepramone, an amphetamine class psychostimulant, and part metamizole, an ampyrone sulfonate group compound with analgesic and antipyretic effects. In combination, the shot provides an acute boost to physical and psychological resilience, even in high stress environments, as well as mild to moderate euphoric effects. Side effects include hyperactivity, sweating, teeth grinding, hypertension, hypotension, irregular heartbeat, nausea, weight loss, and others. SJ-V is distributed, usually as a pen injector, to military personnel set to perform under extreme conditions for longer periods of time. Among the SJ class pens, it is decently tolerated and has acceptable adverse effects compared to its significant desired effects.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major stimulant effects\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate analgesic effects\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor antipsychotic effects\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor hallucinogenic effects\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_sj6">
		<text>SJ-IX Combat Stimulant Shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sj6_descr">
		<text>A military-issue stimulant to increase physical capabilities, alertness, and cognitive performance, intended for use in combat scenarios. It contains part epinephrine, part methamphetamine racetame, a potent central nervous system stimulant, and part metamizole, an ampyrone sulfonate group compound with analgesic and antipyretic effects. In combination, the shot provides an acute boost to physical and psychological resilience, even in high stress environments, as well as mild to moderate euphoric effects. Side effects include hyperactivity, sweating, teeth grinding, hypertension, hypotension, irregular heartbeat, nausea, weight loss, and others. SJ-IX is distributed in limited quantities, usually as a pen injector, to military personnel set to perform under extreme conditions for longer periods of time. Among the SJ class pens, it is decently tolerated but also has notable adverse effects and a moderate addiction and abuse profile.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (injector)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major stimulant effects\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate analgesic effects\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor antipsychotic effects\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor hallucinogenic effects\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_cms">
		<text>Surgical Field Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cms_descr">
		<text>A portable kit that provides medical instruments and supplies to perform minor surgical operations and suturing in the field. It includes a stainless steel scalpel, tweezers, scissors, needle holder, various kinds of wipes, as well as sterile suturing material made from nylon and bandage tape. The kit is designed for use by trained medical professionals for severe injuries and wounds that require immediate attention when a proper field hospital or care facility is not available.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high quality\n
		%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow usage (field kit)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major limb triage\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] major limb recovery\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_paracetamol">
		<text>Paracetamol</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_paracetamol_descr">
		<text>An acetaminophen class antipyretic medication used to treat mild to moderate pain and fever. Paracetamol is an inexpensive over-the-counter drug, it is well tolerated and has a notably low side effects profile with rare cases of nausea, skin rashes, and liver damage when ingested in high doses. In the Zone, it is primarily stocked and used by medical personnel.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_akvatab">
		<text>Modafinil</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_akvatab_descr">
		<text>An eugeroic stimulant that promotes wakefulness and heightened cognition, usually prescriped for the treatment of narcolepsy and excessive daytime fatigue. It is sometimes also prescribed off-label for attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) with mixed efficacy and in adjunctive (combination therapy) treatment of bipolar disorder. Historically, Modafinil has been distributed to military personnel for fatigue management as a safer alternative to amphetamines and to ISS-stationed astronauts to manage circadian dyssynchrony. In the field, it is a viable option to induce alertness and cognitive enhancement with a low side effects and addiction profile.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate stimulant effects\n</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_splint">
		<text>Synthetic Splint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_splint_descr">
		<text>A lightweight splint for immobilizing and stabilizing fractures, sprains, and other injuries, made from synthetic materials and a number of velcro straps to secure it. It is designed to be easily applied and removed, and can be used to support and protect injured limbs.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (velcro straps)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb triage\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_alu_splint">
		<text>SAM Splint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alu_splint_descr">
		<text>A compact, lightweight, and versatile splint for immobilizing and stabilizing fractures, sprains, and other injuries. The SAM Splint is made of a thin core of aluminum alloy, sandwiched between two layers of closed-cell foam. It can be bent into any of three simple curves, becoming extremely strong and supportive for any fractured or injured limb. The splint is durable, waterproof, and radiolucent. It is widely carried in the Zone to treat damage to arms and legs.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast usage (malleable aluminum)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate limb triage\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_joint">
		<text>Cannabis Joint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_joint_descr">
		<text>A hand-rolled joint, filled with Eastern European tobacco sourced from specific Balkan varieties, paired with a moderate amount of low-quality marijuana. Marijuana, or cannabis, contains the psychoactive compound THC, which induces light euphoria, relaxation, and altered perception. Common side effects include dry mouth, red eyes, and increased appetite. The long paper of the Joint was prepared in a somewhat loose and uneven roll. The tobacco used has harsh aromas of burnt vanilla, pine wood, and hints of gasoline. The batch is of low quality, yet still provides some temporary relief from stress and mild pain with minor anxiolytic and antipsychotic effects. The origin or age of the used cannabis are unknown.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] zone-produced item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow usage (smoked joint)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] very minor analgesic effect\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] very minor antipsychotic effects\n
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_marijuana">
		<text>Bag of Marijuana</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_marijuana_descr">
		<text>A few grams of dried marijuana leaves in a small, resealable plastic bag. The leaves are well-preserved and show a vibrant green hue and a distinct, pungent aroma, an indicator for decent quality product. Marijuana, or cannabis, contains the psychoactive compound THC, which induces light euphoria, relaxation, and altered perception. Common side effects include dry mouth, red eyes, and increased appetite. It is rumored that that the Freedom faction employs cultivation of cannabis in hidden indoor greenhouses within the Zone perimeter. Producing items directly inside the Zone has significant appeal when faced with difficult import routes and military checkpoints. Zone-produced cannabis makes up the majority of all cannabis consumed in the Zone. This batch of Marijuana appears to be of average quality and offers a balanced experience for both recreational and medicinal purposes. It provides temporary relief from stress and mild pain with minor anxiolytic and antipsychotic effects.\n \n
		%c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medical item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] zone-produced item\n
		%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow usage (smoked joint)\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor analgesic effect\n
		%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] minor antipsychotic effects\n
		</text>
	</string>
</string_table>